Punit Daga

🛮 +1 (613) 371 05 31 | 💌 pewnit@gmail.com | 🖸 github.com/pewnit | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/punitdaga

Personal Profile

I am a soon-to-be graduate student with a passion for technology and a drive to constantly learn and improve. I have experience in various programming languages and a strong background in data analysis. I am excited to bring my skills and passion to a challenging and dynamic work environment

Education

University of Ottawa Ottawa, Canada

BASc in Computer Engineering

Sept 2018 - May 2024

- · Proficient in C++, Python, and Java
- · Exposure to JavaScript, Android Studio, VHDL, Assembly
- Courses: Introduction to Product Development and Management, Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Systems Design, Data Communications and Networking, and Software Design and Architecture

Work Experience

Ottawa Department of Medicine

Ottawa, Canada

Software Engineer

July 2020 - April 2021

- · Worked with a team of Microsoft Engineers to develop and implement the backend for Azure Devops.
- · Developed a web application using React. js framework and Material UI for an internal tool within the Department of Medicine.
- · Collaborated with cross-functional teams to identify and implement solutions to improve the user experience.
- Technical Skills: React.js, JavaScript, Azure Devops, Material UI, SQL.
- **Soft Skills:** Teamwork, Communication, Agile development.

Smart Living Properties Ottawa, Canada

Network Technician July 2019 - May 2020

- · Provided on-location home internet solutions and resolved Gozi spyware infections on multiple networks.
- Implemented enterprise level network solutions using Cisco Meraki switches.
- Assisted in the troubleshooting and maintenance of network infrastructure.
- Technical Skills: Network Security, Cisco Meraki, Network troubleshooting.
- · Soft Skills: Customer service, Technical support.

LoneHaven Ottawa, Canada

Software Development Lead

January 2022 - December 2022

April 2022 - February 2023

- · Managed student programmers on small projects.
- Overlooked the creation of the company website.
- Contributed to the development and implementation of software solutions for clients.
- Technical Skills: Software Development, Project Management.
- · Soft Skills: Leadership, Teamwork.

Tim Hortons Ottawa, Canada

• Responsible for preparing a variety of baked goods and breakfast items in a fast-paced environment.

- Demonstrated proficiency in time management, food safety, and equipment operation.
- · Collaborated with team members and contributed to maintaining inventory, ensuring product quality and presentation, and assisting with opening and closing duties.
- · Technical Skills: Baking, Food Safety.
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time management.

Projects

Baker

Emergency Call Bell System

Ottawa, Canada

University of Ottawa Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

- Developed a Fitbit app that communicates with an Android companion app to contact emergency services in case a fall is detected.
- Worked on the fall detection and calling system on the phone.
- · Experience with Fitbit API.
- Experience with Android app development.
- Technical Skills: Fitbit API, Android app development.

University of Ottawa Sep 2022 - Apr 2023

• Developed an automated trash sorting system using an Arduino to control the system and a Raspberry Pi to run a neural network and camera for object detection.

- · Created a website and database to track machine locations, update new detections, and display statistics for individual machines.
- Technical Skills: Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Neural Network, Object Detection, Website Development, PostgreSQL.

Skills

Programming Miscellaneous

Programming C++, Java, Python, JavaScript, React. is, C, HTML, CSS, Angular. is, Kotlin, Assembly, VHDL.

Microsoft Office, Cisco Meraki switch, Azure DevOps, Arduino IDE, Android Studio, Fitbit API, Firebase API, MySQL, SQL.

Time management, Food Safety, Equipment operation, Inventory management, Product quality and presentation, Teamwork,

Problem-solving.

Interests_

Soft Skills

Technology

Movie Making and Story Writing

Modern Urbanization

Enthusiast in PC building, repairing devices, and staying up-to-date on the latest technology trends.

Developed skills in film making and storytelling through self-study and online resources such as YouTube.

Interested in the design and development of walkable cities and sustainable public transportation systems.

Languages_

English Native proficiency

Russian Conversational proficiency

Hindi Native proficiency